There is no one like you - Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is no one like him.
Who is like him ?
Good morning, Church !
Viewers, we salute your faith.
Only faith pleases God.
I salute your faith, viewers all over the world.
Hallelujah !
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It takes faith to please God and you are there by faith.
Only faith pleases God.
Nothing and nothing
Thank you Jesus !
Hallelujah !
Last week we talked about - God is Spirit and His worshippers do so in Spirit and truth.
We have to follow that trend.
The hidden truth
The book of John 16 :1
" All this I have told you so that you will not fall away.
That is the hidden truth.
Tell your neighbor : The hidden truth.
I can't hear you.
The hidden truth.
John 16 : 1 "All this I have told you so that you will not fall away.
But when you take your time to read to the end, you will understand what Jesus is talking about.
John 16 : 2 They will put you out of synagogue ;
John 16 : 2 in fact, the time is coming when anyone who kills you
John 16 : 2 will think they are offering a service to God.
Are they not happening now ?
People put whatever they call it...
Blow themselves up !
And said they are going to Heaven.
The Bible is a prophetic word.
Holy man were carried along as they spoke the message that came from Heaven.
Can you see it's a prophetic word ?
If you read with me. You see !
John 16 : 2 .... the time when anyone who kills you
John 16 : 2 will think they are offering a service to God.
Let's read down.
John 16 : 3 They will do such things because they have not known the father.....
John 16 : 3 They will do such things because of what ?
they do not know the father.....
Our Father who are in Heaven, Hallowed be thy name.
The Kingdom comes.
They will think they know Him but they don't.
You can only know him by the Spirit of the father, because He is Spirit.
The Bible says God is Spirit and His worshippers must do so in Spirit and in Truth.
Let's go to verse 33
John 16 : 33 "I have told you these things, so that in me you can have peace,"
That is, if you are not with God, you can not have peace.
If you are not with Him, you cannot have peace.
In Him, you have peace ; in this world, you will have trouble - trouble of all kinds.
John 16 : 33 " But take heart ! I have over come..... "
Take heart.
If you are not with Him, you will have trouble and such trouble will lead to death.
Don't make the mistake of thinking you are out of touch.
You said the devil cannot touch you ; he can touch you but he cannot destroy you.
The touch of that devil will only strengthen your desire and determination for God.
Tell your neighbor !
Don't make the mistake of thinking that you are out of touch.
I can't hear you.
Don't make the mistake of thinking you are out of touch.
Only they can't touch me... this is the mistake we make today.
This is why I called the message "Hidden truth".
That you are sick, you are thinking that you are not a Christian.
Why should I be sick when I am a Christian ? That is a big mistake.
A man can be sick in the body yet be a friend of God.
A man can be poor yet be a candidate of Heaven.
Tell your neighbor once again !
Don't make the mistake of thinking that you are out of touch.
A man can be poor or sick and yet be a favorite of Jesus Christ.
This is the mistake we are making today.
The majority of us are spiritually blind. Spiritually dull.
Dull in comprehension, that is, understanding.
The unseen realm, absolutely closed to our spiritual vision.
We only see the outward effect of the devil but we are blinded to the spiritual causes.
God can often use anything, any foolish thing, to preserve us.
to strengthen our desire and determination,
to stop us for a while and rearrange us for our future.
We misjudged ourselves when we are in such circumstances as hardship.
Why should I face this poverty, my friend.
I go to church regularly.
I am an improved Christian.
I have been baptized. I have stopped smoking.
I have stopped drinking.
Why all this hardship ?
Why ? And why ?
We misjudge ourselves when we are in such circumstances.
Maybe I am not a Christian ; maybe I am a sinner.
Why is this happening to me. Why the sickness, the set back ?
Look at my friend who is not a Christian.
They are drunkards, club goers.
They are making it... they enjoy themselves...
Sin easily hides where there is no trial or temptation.
I mean, where there is no reaction of trial or tribulation.
Like many of us that are here today.
When there is no food on the table and no money in the pocket, we would likely not to come to church.
Jesus is the cause.
When there is no food on the table and no money in the pocket, Jesus be blessed.
In times of prosperity and success, even a wicked man will seem generous and kind.
A wicked man will seem kind and generous in times of prosperity and success.
When there is no money in the pocket or food on the table, this will separate impurities.
Whatever your situation as a believer - all are for your obedience to God.
Tell your neighbor !
Whatever my situation as a believer - all are for my obedience to God.
They are not meant to kill you or destroy you.
Your struggle should make you stronger if you are a Christian.
What are you going through ?
It is for your obedience to God.
We grow in character through obedience.
Open your Bible to the Book of Hebrews 5 : 8
Though Jesus was a son, a son of God yet He learned obedience by the things which He suffered.
He was rejected.
Are you talking of slanderer's remarks ?
Jay at him !
If you say you are the son of God, come down from the cross !
Jay at him ! You ! You !
Name calling !
Oftentimes, we run from the things that will strengthen our lives.
We run from the very things that will bring strength to our lives.
Such as pain and trials of all kinds.
There are things that bring strength to our lives.
What are those things ?
Things like trials, temptations, persecutions, name calling, those foolish things.
Wyen you know this is trial,
you will do anything to avoid it.
Another words, as a Christian, there are things that bring strength.
When you dodge it, you are postponing the evil day.
You are postponing the evil.
You will meet it tomorrow, somewhere !
You see trial coming, it's destined.
Because you need to know, you need to see.
Because we are spiritually blind. Spiritually dull.
Dull in comprehension.
When you dodge it, you are postponing the evil day.
These are the things many of us are facing today.
Those are the things you should've faced at your younger days.
Those troubles you should've encountered when you were very young.
If you dodge them (troubles), you use your ability, power
you have everything, you have connections.
You dodge them. You avoid them.
They are the ones (troubles), you are facing today. You can't avoid them.
You are postponing them.
Don't make the mistake of thinking that you are out of touch.
Because I am a Christian. Because I am this...
You think you are a Christian. You live right.
The righteousness you are talking about is a gift.
It's not the work of righteousness.
It's not what you work for.
It's not what you labour for.
It's not what you study. It's not what you've learned.
We grow in character through obedience.
Physical growth is a function of time.
Intellectual growth is a function of learning.
Spiritual growth is a function of obedience to God's will.
Don't misjudge yourself when you are in such circumstances as failure, disappointment, sickness.
Don't begin to ask, "Am I not a Christian ? Why should all these things happen to me ?"
Look at those people who have made it. They don't live right !
How do you know you live right ?
Living right is not what we work for.
It's a gift of God.
You said, "I am living right. I stop smoking."
How do you know who stop you from smoking ?
You have the power to stop yourself ?
No !
It is grace.
And you say you are living right ?
It's a gift from God !
It's not what we work for.
If it's what you've worked for, you can boast about !
When you work for something. You (claim credit for it). You fight for it.
By merit.
I read it. I must make it. You fight for it.
In this case, our lives, it's by grace.
What is happening to you cannot take your position as a child of God.
It cannot.
Don't judge your Christian life by your situation.
This is too much, I am not a Christian. How do you know ?
Because of what you are facing, you are not a Christian ?
Because of what has happened to you, you are not a Christian ?
Because of what you are facing, because of the situation you are in, you are not a Christian ?
Don't allow your situation to rule you.
God refines us with situation like that.
The reaction of your situation on you separates impurities.
Tell your neighbor.
The reaction of my situation on me separates impurities
and allows the character of God to grow in my life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your situation cannot say you are not a Christian.
My situation cannot determine my Christian life.
I can't hear you.
My situation separates impurities and allows the character of God to grow in my life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, the question... that ..
Because of my situation !
I don't know if I am a Christian ?
Why all this is happening to you ? Why you are saying this ?
It's discouraging your journey, your journey as a Christian.
You are judging yourself....Misjudging.
Whereas you are a Christian.
But because of your situation you are now thinking,
"I don't know whether or not I am a Christian? Why all this is happening to me?"
The Holy Spirit needs a free spirit.
When your thinking, "Am I a Christian ?" Your spirit is in bondage.
Your spirit must be free to attract the spirit of God.
If your spirit is not free, you cannot attract the spirit of God.
You cannot have anything to do with God ; you cannot even pray.
You need free spirit.
My Christian, why all this happens to me ?
Why all the setback.
Why this ? Why that ? Why this ? Why that ?
That's not from the free spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Bible says no temptation can seize you except the temptation that is common to man.
Stop misjudging yourself.
Tell your neighbor.
I can't hear you !
Stop misjudging yourself.
This is the trap of satan - a common trick satan is using today.
Because Jesus is coming very very soon.
On the last day.
Satan is now coming out with common trick.
When he gives you sickness, that sickness will tell you, "You are not a Christian."
You too will accept. And start to walk the way of unbelievers.
Because of the voice.
If something says you are not a Christian and you accept you are not a Christian - why do you still want to Iive a Christian life ?
If I am talking to you let me see your hand.
Disappointment keeps telling you, "Can you see?
See your friend is doing well? His business is going well. You saying you're a Christian. You're not a Christian!" You too agree, "Yes, I'm not a Christian".
This is a common trick of satan.
You sleep in the night and you have nightmare.
Somebody comes to embarrass you. You find it very embarrassing.
By the time you wake up, you refuse to pray.
What about the one (prayer) I offered yesterday ? It gives me nightmare.
The prayer I offered yesterday. That prayer gives me nightmare.
Which I can't pray again.
I have been fasting for 3 days. The last day I am supposed to hear from God. Look at the embarrassment.
Stop misjudging yourself because you are disappointed.
Why are you thinking that you are out of touch ?
When the Bible says in this world, there will be trouble.
Are you not in the world ?
Jesus said to His disciples, "I pray your faith will not fail".
That shows there will be something that challenges your faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He said to His disciples, "I pray your faith will not fail - you will not be abandon me".
That is what He is saying, 'I pray you will not abandon me'.
It shows that something is coming that will tempt you to renounce Him.
To say, "I am not a Christian".
They can only touch you ; they cannot destroy you.
Sickness will come to touch you ; affliction will come to touch you.
Temptation will come to touch you ; trials of any kind will come to touch you.
but cannot impair you.
They can only separate impurities and allow the character of God in your life to grow.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A true Christian is tested by his ability to face situations.
That is a true Christian.
It's like somebody who goes through school from secondary school to university.
No examation. How would you be promoted ?
When you go to school without exams. Would you be promoted ?
Trials and temptations are a test to promote you.
Your faith life needs to be tested.
To test you, all these foolish things are the examation.
You can never live and be out of touch. ( by evilness)
You will be touched. Satan will touch you. Trial of any kind will touch you. Affliction will touch you.
It can only touch you. Just touch.
That touch is to separate impurities and allow the character of God in your life to grow.
Rise up !
Thank you Jesus !
Hallelujah !
I want to offer a prayer for you.
Jesus, give them a hearing heart -
A heart to obey this Word, a heart to do the Word says, in Jesus' name.
That is my prayer for you.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today.
And stay up-to-date for the latest prophecies, deliverances, service and testimonies from the SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV, changing lives, changing nations, and changing the world.